export const LEATHERWORKA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The state in which pelt is made neutral is through the process of",
A: "pickling.",
B: "fatmongering.",
C: "curing.",
D: "bating.",
answer: "D. bating.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following is suitable for splitting leather?",
A: "Shaving knife",
B: "Skiving knife",
C: "Head knife",
D: "Band knife",
answer: "D. Band knife",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A process in which leather is separated into layers is termed",
A: "shaving.",
B: "skiving.",
C: "splitting.",
D: "splicing.",
answer: "C. splitting.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. If hides and skins are tanned, they are resistant to",
A: "bacteria and water.",
B: "heat and light.",
C: "light and bacteria.",
D: "water and heat",
answer: "A. bacteria and water.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Imitation leathers appeal mostly to the sense of",
A: "kinesthetic.",
B: "sight.",
C: "smell.",
D: "touch.",
answer: "B. sight.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A groove conceals",
A: "blanket stitches.",
B: "overcast stitches.",
C: "running stitches.",
D: "whip stitches.",
answer: "A. blanket stitches.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The tool used for tracing designs on leather is",
A: "beveller.",
B: "modeler.",
C: "seeder.",
D: "shader.",
answer: "C. tracer.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Plating makes leather",
A: "coarse.",
B: "flexible.",
C: "porous.",
D: "smooth.",
answer: "D. smooth.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following animals produces exotic leather?",
A: "Crocodile",
B: "Buffalo",
C: "Bison",
D: "Fox",
answer: "A. Crocodile",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Leather off-cuts are useful in the decorating process of",
A: "embossing.",
B: "applique.",
C: "seeding.",
D: "shaving.",
answer: "B. applique.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. What tool is used in pressing down the background in flat modelling?",
A: "Modeller",
B: "Seeder",
C: "Shader",
D: "Stipper",
answer: "A. Modeller",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The epidermis is removed during",
A: "dehairing.",
B: "fleshing.",
C: "liming.",
D: "washing.",
answer: "A. dehairing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following are methods offlaying.",
A: "Casing and bating",
B: "Pickling and ripping",
C: "Peeling and salting",
D: "Ripping and casing",
answer: "D. Ripping and casing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Ante-mortem defects of hides and skins is caused by",
A: "barbed wire scratches.",
B: "faulty drying.",
C: "improper flaying.",
D: "inadequate curing.",
answer: "A. barbed wire scratches.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The property of leather which makes it withstand flexing and wear is",
A: "water resistance.",
B: "tensile strength.",
C: "porosity.",
D: "smoothness.",
answer: "B. tensile strength.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The function of a leather talisman is",
A: "social.",
B: "spiritual.",
C: "economic.",
D: "educational.",
answer: "B. spiritual.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following fasteners is conveniently used on compartments in a leather bag?",
A: "Buckle",
B: "Press stud",
C: "Toggle and loop",
D: "Zip",
answer: "C. Toggle and loop",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The reason for buffing leather is to",
A: "achieve a suede effect only.",
B: "improve its tensile strength.",
C: "reduce blemish on its grain side.",
D: "reduce its thickness.",
answer: "C. reduce blemish on its grain side.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following is a step in carving?",
A: "Casing the leather",
B: "Piercing the leather",
C: "Thonging the outline",
D: "Using a chisel to cut the leather",
answer: "D. Using a chisel to cut the leather",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Animals in the wild are hunted, for their",
A: "bones.",
B: "horns.",
C: "skins.",
D: "wool.",
answer: "C. skins.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. When designing a wall hanging, consideration is first given to",
A: "attractiveness.",
B: "cost.",
C: "use.",
D: "weight.",
answer: "C. use.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following animal skins is best suited for the production of a traditional drum?",
A: "Antelope",
B: "Crocodile",
C: "Horse",
D: "Python",
answer: "A. Antelope",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A post-mortem defect of hides and skins is caused by",
A: "brand marks.",
B: "inadequate curing.",
C: "sore marks.",
D: "scabies.",
answer: "B. inadequate curing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is normally sharpened with both emery cloth and file?",
A: "Chisel",
B: "Modeller",
C: "Skivingknife",
D: "Spring punch",
answer: "A. Chisel",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The eyelet protects the",
A: "article.",
B: "hole.",
C: "lace.",
D: "thong.",
answer: "B. hole.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Swivel cuts are made with the knife",
A: "pushed away from the cutter.",
B: "pulled towards the cutter.",
C: "tilted to the right.",
D: "tilted to the left",
answer: "B. pulled towards the cutter.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The best stage to dye a piece of leather which will be punched is",
A: "after punching.",
B: "after drying.",
C: "during punching.",
D: "during tanning.",
answer: "D. during tanning.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Indicate the right order of preserving sheep skins for export",
A: "flayed, dehaired and limed.",
B: "fleshed, cured, delimed and dried.",
C: "salted, limed, dehaired and dried.",
D: "pickled, salted and dried.",
answer: "C. salted, limed, dehaired and dried.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Pick out the two types of rivets from the following options.",
A: "Dome and base",
B: "Split and tubular",
C: "Swivel and stud",
D: "Toggle and loop",
answer: "B. Split and tubular",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Select the most appropriate substitute for a modeller from the options below.",
A: "Bonefolder",
B: "Drive punch",
C: "Traced",
D: "Wooden mallet31. Slit holes for thonging around comers and curves are made with the",
answer: "D. Wooden mallet",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. *******************************",
A: "four-prong chisel.",
B: "three-prong chisel.",
C: "two-prong chisel.",
D: "one-prong chisel.",
answer: "A. four-prong chisel.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The first stage in the production of a leather article is",
A: "sketching.",
B: "finishing.",
C: "decorating.",
D: "cutting.",
answer: "A. sketching.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Grooves are made on leather with a",
A: "lid.",
B: "chisel.",
C: "tracer.",
D: "gouge.",
answer: "D. gouge.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Leathers are imitated by",
A: "embossing.",
B: "carving.",
C: "scorching.",
D: "tooling.",
answer: "C. scorching.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following is a decorations on leather?",
A: "Buckle",
B: "D-ring",
C: "Scorching",
D: "Swivel",
answer: "C. Scorching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Bating makes the skin",
A: "hard.",
B: "heavy.",
C: "pliable.",
D: "translucent.",
answer: "C. pliable.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following steps follow each other in succession in leather production?",
A: "Designing and sketching",
B: "Decorating and polishing",
C: "Finishing and trimming",
D: "Tracing and cutting",
answer: "A. Designing and sketching",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The most suitable method of storing leatherwork tools is to",
A: "clean and neatly pack them in a box.",
B: "keep them in sheaths.",
C: "oil, wrap and keep them under the cutting board.",
D: "sharpen and hang them on a rack.",
answer: "A. clean and neatly pack them in a box.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Temporary assembling of leather parts is done using",
A: "gum erratic.",
B: "rubber cement.",
C: "rivet.",
D: "thong.",
answer: "D. thong.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Leather is shaved in order to",
A: "increase value.",
B: "increase thickness.",
C: "reduce bulk.",
D: "reduce cost.",
answer: "C. reduce bulk.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]